





Senior management professional, over 18 years of experience in Solution Delivery and Delivery Center Management. Co-designed and developed key Technology and led the IT dept. of startup which was valued at \$17 Million in 3 years time.



Total Experience: 19 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Industrial Relations and

Notice Period: 3 Months

Personnel Management]

Current Designation: Manager, Digital Engineering & RPA

solutions

Current Company: IBM,

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Mysore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Program Manager, Solution Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, T Delivery Management, Business — Intelligence, Process Improvement, IT Strategy Planning, IT Budgeting, IT Program Management, Software Development

Life Cycle,

Verified : L. Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Senior management professional with over 18 years of experience in roles as Solution Delivery and Delivery Center Management Expert involved in solution consulting on Distributed Systems, Blockchain. Co-designed and developed whole

system and Key Technology for a startup, and led the startup to be valued at more than \$17 Million in 3 years time. Anatural thinker capable of technical, logical and creative thinking, developing out of the box products

Work Experience

IBM, as Manager, Digital Engineering & RPA solutions Apr 2009 to Till Date

career Graph:

 ${\it Manager, Digital Engineering \& RPA solutions, IBM China, Jun 2018 - Present}$

Manager - Digital Solutions, IBM China Centre, Apr 2013 - Jun 2018

PeWPgM- Business transformation - IT @ Office of CIO, IBM India Ltd, Apr 2009 - Apr 2013

Accountabilities:

? Define and ensure compliance to group IT strategy, evaluating user requirements to align with changing operational needs. Conduct suitability and viability of corporate systems and develop proposals for IT projects.

Develop and manage IT budget and financial management at location level in accordance with global strategy. Develop and maintain vendor relations for Talent and Knowledge management.

Manage programs timelines and delivery excellence.

Sponsor/Client Relations Management

Key Accomplishments

Successfully developed and implemented 4 Digital products with user base between 5 to 15,000 users worth budget of \$5 Million. Generated savings of 80000 hours for the client by implementing automation solutions.

Co-designed and developed full IT system and Key Technology for a startup and led the IT dept. and achieved high degree of reliability in systems and infrastructure

Touch Media as Project Manager Oct 2003 to Oct 2007

Functioned as IT Leader / Project Manager involved in co-designing and developing IT system and Key Technology for the startup leading to valuation of the start up to \$17+ Million in a span of 3 years

^ Back to Top

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Education

· · · ·

PG: PG Diploma (Industrial Relations and Personnel Management) from Bangalore University in 2001

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Master diploma in Software Engineering Agile Coach and Team Coach

IBM- Mini MBA

Agile Scrum Master (License 000404562 Leading and Managing Effectively in China

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA		7 Year(s)
Agile Coach		4 Year(s)
Scrum Master		5 Year(s)
Distributed System Architecture		4 Year(s)
New product Development		10 Year(s)
Team Coach		4 Year(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert			✓
kannada	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Mandarin	Proficient			✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: China
Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.